Jonathan Phillips, PMP

Cell 206.670.2355 jphillips103@earthlink.net

244 Blanchard Street Seattle, WA 98102

Senior Manager, Project/Program

More than 10 years of experience applying people, process, problem-solving, and technical skills to improve individual, team and organizational performance. Designed, developed, and implemented technical infrastructure that led to organization being twice distinguished among the top 100 Managed Service Providers (MSPs) in the world. Personally recognized as one of the top 250 people in the MSP community by MSPmentor. An impassioned team leader who mentors with purpose and understands that strong working relationships create great teams and produce exceptional results.

Strengths

Contingency Planner... Project Evangelist & Team Builder... Research & Strategic Analysis Provide Structure, Direction & Vision... Problem Solver... Customer Facing...

"Jonathan is a visionary who can and does lead, provoke, and enable people at the intersection of technology and humanity." William Iravs, Co-Founder and CEO, BA Consulting Group, LLC

Work Experience

TIERAONLINE, LLC (Acquired Virrula Communications in 12/2007.) 12/2007—5/2009 Company has three divisions; ERP software and custom software development, business process consulting, and managed service provider.

Senior Project Manager/Business Process Analyst

- Managed 3 diverse divisions, 26 people, \$1.5M+ budgets, full P&L responsibility.
- Built productive remote software development teams by managing performance using results-based metrics and utilizing remote collaboration tools such as SharePoint.
- Resolved production problems with plant floor manufacturing by performing root-cause analysis of work flow issues. Utilized techniques that included work flow analysis, quality assurance, and change management.
- Improved call center responsiveness by 22% while center underwent 300% increase in customer demand. Analyzed and documented traffic flow to devise a right-time staffing solution with a minimal increase in personnel.
- Designed and built an in-house category management system for a tree fruit supplier that
 provided sales evaluation service at less than half the cost of other vendors. System
 replaced manual process knowledge lost due to retirement of a key employee.
- Conceived and implemented a 90-day customer satisfaction program to proactively seek customer feedback based on 'Managing IT before it breaks.' Increased customer satisfaction by 32% via feedback surveys and forward planning by 12%.
- Managed team for ERP software redesign that included a large number of releases—40 over 9 months with a budget of \$1M. Utilized JAD sessions and RAD techniques to quickly gather multiple customers' feedback and incorporate into next release.
- Enlarged in-house hosting platform to 1200+ desktops, 120+ servers, 75+ customer locations. Increased customer base by 35% by expanding Software as a Service (SaaS) and Hardware as a Service (HaaS) company offerings.

"As a project manager in the firms where I was also the managing partner, I developed a unique perspective on the importance of managing resources, schedules, change and quality in such a way that every project contributes to the success of the company." Jonathan Phillips

Key Clients: Compass Aerospace, Thyssenkrupp, GCM North America, Solid State Controls



Cell 206.670.2355 jphillips103@earthlink.net

VIRRULA COMMUNICATIONS, Inc. (Acquired by Tieraonline in 12/2007.) 9/1998—12/2007 Managed Service Provider for hosted solutions.

Senior Project Manager

- Designed an employee satisfaction program to increase individual productivity and team commitment. Conducted individual assessment of skills, talents, and interests then matched them to organization and project needs.
- Consolidated up to 20 non-integrated sales processes—technology, infrastructure and people—into a centralized sales desk. New capabilities included automating large image transfers which, crucial part of the sales cycle for tree fruit manufacturers.
- Created a worry-free backup and disaster recovery (BDR) system. Used existing software to design a new BDR system that virtualized server image and acted as failover production server. Seamless transition and fault-tolerance delivered uninterrupted business services.
- Introduced a new 'Complete Care Package' program to deliver customized enterprise class IT to small and medium (SMB) businesses. Flat monthly fee service enabled companies to receive enterprise support and service at an affordable price.

Key Clients: Shell Oil Dist, NCW Hospital, Perimeter eSecurity, Dole NW, US Bank.

SOUTHWEST INTERNET, INC.

1/1995—9/1998

President

Regional Internet Service Provider (ISP) for 2500+ customers.

Built company from start-up and sold as a thriving concern.

Technology Profile

Software: Microsoft Office, Excel, All Microsoft OS, Server 2003&8, Exchange 2003&7, Project, SQL 2000&5, SharePoint MOSS 2007, Cisco IOS, Vmware ESX, XenServer & others

Hardware: IBM, Dell, Lenovo, HP, Cisco, Supermicro

Software development: .NET, ASP, C++, SQL 2005+, Access, Crystal & SQL reporting, VB6 Technologies/Protocols: Active Directory, AD-for SSO, DNS, DHCP, TCP/IP, IPS/IDS, VPN, IPSEC, policy based routing, bandwidth shaping, redundant Internet connections, OSPF

Project Management

Project Methodologies: PMI, WBS, Cost Breakdown, Waterfall, SDLC, JAD, RAD, draw-seethink-plan, strategic planning, SOW, RFQ, RFP, recruiting, championing, forecasting.

Project types:

- Budgets to \$1.5M
- Business Impacts to 6 million 600+ Seat Accounting
- 1200+ Seat Infrastructures 75 Seat Sales Organizations Manufacturing & Service
- 120+ Servers
- 45 Seat EHR, Medical Records
- 75 Seat CRM Installs
- 150+ Seat ERP Installs

- Change & Control Management
- Market and Business Development
- Acquisition and Mergers
- Not-for-Profit & Banking
- Industry
- Tree Fruit
 - Healthcare & Aerospace

Education and Achievements

Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist (MCTS), 5/2007 Microsoft Small Business Specialist (MSBS), 5/2007 Project Management Professional (PMP), No. 315620 1/2006 Fortinet Certified System Engineer (FCSE), 12/2003







America's #1 Online Resume Builder

With Cover Letters

- Easy-to-use, guides you through step-by-step
- Resume templates, writing samples and tips
- One-click designs for the professional look you want
- Start from scratch or upload your resume



Already have an account?











Phone and Chat Hours: 7 Days a Week 6am to midnight EST



Write a resume - in minutes

Your resume is often your first and only chance to make a great impression on an employer. Managers will scan your resume for just 10 seconds to see if you're right for the job.

That's why your resume needs to be attractive and stand out. It needs to be well-written and highlight your skills to your best advantage.

The problem is most people don't know how to write a great resume and don't have the design skills to make it look professional.

- Our Resume Builder is designed to make resume-writing fast and easy.
- We match you with the right template and, in just one click, you can choose a professional design that will help you win the job.
- Our unique Text Tuner™ allows you to choose from hundreds of expert-written examples - no more writer's block!

Get the "most impressive resume builder on the market today". There's no risk; no obligation. We're so confident that you'll love our resume builder that you can try it for FREE.

According to our partners..."the most impressive resume builder on the market today."

onTargetiobs

YAHOO! hotjobs EmploymentGuide.com

Ret-Temps Joined

Customer Reviews

Job.com

"I was completely unaware of what companies are looking for in a resume. This product helped me word and format my professional resume and the examples were extremely useful. Overall, this is a great product. I would highly recommend these services." - A. Danihels

"This resume tool is so much better than templates - just upload or enter your resume content and you get your choice of designs. It's magical! Anyone can benefit from this tool: from students to executives!" - Belinda Yanda

View more reviews >



